Front End Developer (JavaScript, React.JS)

Yana Kozarenko Cambridge Email LinkedIn GitHub

Summary:

Front End Developer / Engineer, keen on working with a full development product life cycle, designing and developing high-quality user interfaces. Tech stack: JavaScript, React.JS, CSS3, Tailwind, MUI, Bootstrap, WordPress, responsive and adaptive design.

Agile (Scrum, Kanban) team experience.

Skills:

- Front End development experience
- React.JS
- JavaScript
- Good knowledge of software engineering best practices
- Agile (Scrum, Kanban) environment
- Excellent communication and collaboration skills

Education:

- Fullstack Web Development, University of Helsinki (currently attending)
- Fullstack Web Development, Codecademy (currently attending)
- Frontend Web Development Bootcamp, PurpleBeard, UK (Completion Date: 7.2023)
- Frontend Web Developer, Codecademy (Completion Date: 1.2023)
- Frontend Web Development Foundations, EdX (Completion Date: 10.2021)
- ICAgile certificate Agile, Scrum, Kanban, ICAgile (Completion Date: 2020)
- Marketing Specialist University KROK, Ukraine
- Bcs in Social Science and Psychology, Ukraine

Projects:

- <u>Happy and Healthy Recipes</u> (2023) Developed a 3-page web application using ReactJS and REST APIs, focusing on responsive design and collaborative development using Git. UI-UX, REST API, Local Storage.
- Oassis.uk Charity (2023) Customised web application, installed plugins to enhance website functionality and meet company goals.
- Vanilla JS Challenges Project (2023) multi-page web application using pure JS.

Experience:

Junior Frontend Developer, Purple Beard Frontend Bootcamp (April 2023 - July 2023)

- Developed web applications using JavaScript, React.JS, HTML, CSS, and frameworks Bootstrap, MUI, and Tailwind.
- Fetched data from APIs to enhance application functionality.
- Tested and debugged the project to meet the requirements
- Collaborated with a team to implement responsive designs and ensure code quality

Volunteer Frontend Developer, Oasis UK Charity (2023)

 Customised WordPress web application, installed plugins to enhance website functionality and meet company goals, improved UI-UX.

Customer Service Assistant, Scotsdales Garden Center (July 2022 - January 2024)

 Attend customer needs by answering the queries and resolving any emerging problems that the customer accounts might face with accuracy and efficiency.

Marketing Specialist, Italmotors Ukraine, official automotive Fiat, Alfa Romeo, Lancia, Skoda (2014-2019)

- Collaborated with UI/UX Designers and Software Engineers to develop a responsive, attractive for customers, well-functioning website to meet the requirements of official importers, satisfy customer needs and increase sales.
- Managed digital and offline advertising campaigns.
- Analysed UI-UX using Google and Yandex tools and provided improvements.
- The marketing team achieved first place in the ranking of FIAT car dealerships in Ukraine, based on a general sales rating, from 2014 to 2019.

Additional Information:

- Passionate about Computer Science and Software Development.
- Interested in AI, and also in AR, VR, MR.
- Strong problem-solving skills.
- Effective communicator with the ability to provide concise and timely feedback.

References: Available upon request.